<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_quest_name">
        <string lang="en">Grampz</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_shop_name">
        <string lang="en">Nikko</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_pvp_name">
        <string lang="en">Brenne</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_craft_name">
        <string lang="en">Grent</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_fusion_name">
        <string lang="en">Prof. Haile</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_mounts_name">
        <string lang="en">Quinn</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_rifts_name">
        <string lang="en">Nyxn</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_gauntlet_name">
        <string lang="en">Agnar</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_fishing_name">
        <string lang="en">Ishmael</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_mystic_name">
        <string lang="en">Derwin</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_leaderboard_name">
        <string lang="en">Ingrid</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_brawl_name">
        <string lang="en">Xaren</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_npc_fishing_shop_name">
        <string lang="en">Grella</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_goblin_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!400!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r1_goblin_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!500!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r1_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!540!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_goblin_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1200!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1240!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r3_goblin_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1700!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r3_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1740!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r4_goblin_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2400!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2440!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n1_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!10!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n2_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!20!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!40!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n6_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!50!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!80!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n10_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!110!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!120!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n1_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!140!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n2_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!150!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!160!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n6_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!180!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!200!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n9_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!230!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n11_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!210!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!240!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n2_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!250!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!280!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n5_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!290!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n6_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!300!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!320!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n9_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!330!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n10_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!340!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!360!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n1_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1000!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n2_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1010!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1030!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n6_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1040!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1070!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n10_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1080!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1110!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n3_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1520!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1530!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n7_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1550!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1570!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n11_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1590!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!1610!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n3_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2220!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n4_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2230!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n5_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2240!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n6_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2260!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n7_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2250!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n8_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2270!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n11_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2300!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n12_boss_name">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!2310!familiar!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_player_desc">
        <string lang="en">...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ermm... hey, you! Haven't seen you around here before. You new to this area?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hum... Salut, toi ! Je ne te connais pas. Tu es nouveau ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Ehm... Salve! Non ti avevo mai visto da queste parti. Sei qui da poco?</string>
        <string lang="de">Ähm ... hey, du! Dich hab ich hier noch nie gesehen. Bist du neu hier?</string>
        <string lang="es">Esto... ¡Eh, tú! No me suena haberte visto por aquí antes. ¿Acabas de llegar?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Opa... ei, você aí! Nunca te vi por aqui antes. Você é novo aqui?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Don't talk much do yah? Ah, well thats alright. I'll do enough talkin' for the both of us!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu n'as pas l'air très bavard. Peu importe, je parlerai pour deux !</string>
        <string lang="it">Non parli molto, eh? Bah, fa lo stesso, parlo abbastanza io per tutti e due.</string>
        <string lang="de">Du redest nicht viel, was? Hey, ist okay. Ich rede genug für uns beide!</string>
        <string lang="es">No hablas mucho, ¿eh? Bueno, no pasa nada. ¡Ya me encargo yo de hablar por los dos!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Não gosta muito de conversar né? Não tem problema. Pode deixar que eu falo por nós dois!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_frame_3_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">I reckon if you want some respect round here you'll have to prove yourself first.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Si tu veux te faire respecter ici, tu vas devoir faire tes preuves.</string>
        <string lang="it">Se vuoi che ti rispettino da queste parti dovrai dimostrare quanto vali.</string>
        <string lang="de">Wenn du hier respektiert werden willst, musst du dich erst einmal beweisen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Si quieres que te respeten por estos lares, primero tendrás que demostrar tu valía.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Mas se você quer ganhar o respeito de todos, primeiro vai ter que provar que merece.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_frame_3_content_3_desc">
        <string lang="en">Do me a favor will yah? Take care of that pesky !familiar!10!familiar! lurking nearby. He's been a real pain in me bum.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Rends-moi service, tu veux ? Occupe-toi de ce maudit !familiar!10!familiar! qui rôde dans les parages. Il commence à me taper sur les nerfs.</string>
        <string lang="it">Fammi un favore, va bene? Sistema quel maledetto !familiar!10!familiar! che sta da queste parti. È una vera spina nel didietro.</string>
        <string lang="de">Tu mir einen Gefallen, ja? Erledige diesen lästigen !familiar!10!familiar!, der hier herumschleicht. Der geht mir echt auf die Nerven.</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Me puedes hacer un favor? Encárgate de ese incordio de !familiar!10!familiar! que acecha por aquí cerca. Ha sido un auténtico plasta.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Aliás, me faz um favor? Dá um sumiço naquele !familiar!10!familiar! pentelho que fica passeando por aqui? Que bicho pé no saco.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_fusion_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">EGAD! You found a schematic! Now all you need are the ingredients!</string>
        <string lang="fr">OUAH ! Tu as trouvé un schéma ! Eh bien, il ne te reste plus qu'à réunir les ingrédients !</string>
        <string lang="it">CRIBBIO! Hai trovato un progetto! Ora ti mancano solo gli ingredienti!</string>
        <string lang="de">SIEH AN! Du hast einen Bauplan gefunden! Jetzt brauchst du nur noch die Zutaten!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡ANDA! ¡Has encontrado un esquemático! ¡Ahora, solo necesitas los ingredientes!</string>
        <string lang="pt">NOSSA SENHORA! Você achou uma fórmula! Agora só precisa achar os ingredientes!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_rifts_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">So mortal, you've proven yourself strong enough for my trials. Enter and prove your worth.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Très bien, mortel, puisque tu as réussi mes épreuves, entre et montre-moi ce que tu vaux.</string>
        <string lang="it">Ebbene, mortale, hai dimostrato di essere all'altezza delle mie prove. Entra e sapremo quanto vali.</string>
        <string lang="de">Also, Sterblicher, du hast dich als stark genug für meine Prüfungen erwiesen. Tritt ein und beweise dich.</string>
        <string lang="es">Bueno, mortal, has demostrado tener la fuerza necesaria para enfrentarte a mis pruebas. Adelante, demuestra tu valía.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Caro mortal, você provou ser digno de participar dos meus desafios. Entre e mostre toda a sua bravura.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_gauntlet_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Yah, OK string bean. You tink you are vheady?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Bon, OK, jeune pousse. Tu te sens prêt ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Bene, pikolo fuscello. Tu pensi ke sei pronto, ja?</string>
        <string lang="de">Ja, gut, okay, Bohnenstange. Bist du bereit oder was, ey?</string>
        <string lang="es">Veamoh, ehpagueti. ¿Creeh que estáh preparao?</string>
        <string lang="pt">E aí, frangote? Tá achando que vai aguentá?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_gauntlet_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Get to da Gauntlet!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Vas-y, essaie de relever le défi !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Afronta il cimento!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ab in den Spießrutenlauf!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡¡A por el Duelo!!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Bora pro Coliseu!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_familiarstable_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Alright, alright! You're a pesky little bugger aren't ya!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">D'accord d'accord! Vous êtes un petit bêtisant ennuyeux, n'est-ce pas?</string>
        <string lang="it">Va bene, va bene! Sei un malizioso fastidio, non sei ya !?</string>
        <string lang="de">Also gut! Du bist ein nervtötender kleiner Bugger sind nicht ya !?</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Bien bien! Eres un maldito insípido no eres ya !?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Tudo bem, tudo bem! Você é um pequeno insensato, você não é?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_familiarstable_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Fine! I'll let you use my Stable. BUT let me warn you!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Bien! Je vais vous laisser utiliser mon Écurie MAIS permettez-moi de vous prévenir!</string>
        <string lang="it">Bene! Ti permetterò di utilizzare la mia Stalla. MA permettimi di avvisarti!</string>
        <string lang="de">Fein! Ich lasse dich meinen Stall benutzen. ABER lass mich dich warnen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Multa! Te dejaré usar mi Caballeriza. PERO me dejó advertirle!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Bem! Vou deixar você usar meu Estábulo. MAS deixe-me avisá-lo!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_familiarstable_frame_3_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">When a bunch of the same Familiars hang out in my Stable they become more powerful, weird huh?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Quand un groupe de même Familiers traine dans mon Écurie ils deviennent plus puissants, étranges, hein?</string>
        <string lang="it">Quando un gruppo di stessi Famigli appendono nella mia Stalla diventano più potenti, strano eh?</string>
        <string lang="de">Wenn ein Bündel der gleichen Schutzgeister in meinem Stall hängen, werden sie mächtiger, seltsam huh?</string>
        <string lang="es">Cuando un grupo de los mismos Compañeros se cuelgan en mi Caballeriza se vuelven más poderosos, ¿eh extraño?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Quando um monte dos mesmos Familiares anda no meu Estábulo eles se tornam mais poderosos, estranho, hein?</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_intro_brawl_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! You dare speak to The XAREN!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! Vous osez parler au XAREN!?</string>
        <string lang="it">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! Si osere parlare con il XAREN!?</string>
        <string lang="de">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! Du wagst es, mit dem XAREN zu sprechen!?</string>
        <string lang="es">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! Te atreves a hablar con el XAREN!?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Muhahahahahahaha! MUHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!! Você ousa falar com o XAREN!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_brawl_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The Xaren has a test for you. Defeat The Xaren's Giant Orc Monster and The Xaren will reward you with the greatest gift of all!! *legendary* loot!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">le Xaren vous présente un test. Battez le monstre orc géant de Xaren et le Xaren vous récompensera avec le plus grand cadeau de tous! Pieu *legendary* !!</string>
        <string lang="it">il Xaren ha un test per te. Sconfiggi il mostro gigante del orc di Xaren e il Xaren ti ricompenserà con il più grande dono di tutti !! *legendary* saccheggio !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Xaren hat einen Test für Sie. Besiege das Xarens riesige Ork-Monster und das Xaren belohnt dich mit dem größten Geschenk von allen! *legendary* Beute !!</string>
        <string lang="es">el Xaren tiene una prueba para usted. ¡Derrota al monstruo gigante del Xaren y el Xaren te recompensará con el mejor regalo de todos! *legendary* botín!</string>
        <string lang="pt">O Xaren tem uma prova para você. Derrote o gigante monstro orc da Xaren e o Xaren irá recompensá-lo com o maior presente de todos !! *legendary* loot !!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_brawl_frame_3_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">And if you are lucky, The Xaren's friendship!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Et si vous êtes chanceux, l'amitié de Xaren!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
        <string lang="it">E se sei fortunato, l'amicizia di Xaren!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
        <string lang="de">Und wenn Sie Glück haben, die Freundschaft von Xaren!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
        <string lang="es">Y si tienes suerte, la amistad de la Xaren!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
        <string lang="pt">E se você tiver sorte, a amizade do Xaren!! Muhahahahahahaha.</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_intro_invasion_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The town is under attack! We must unite to defend our home!</string>
        <string lang="fr">La ville est attaquée! Nous devons nous unir pour défendre notre maison!</string>
        <string lang="it">La città è sotto attacco! Dobbiamo unirci per difendere la nostra casa!</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Stadt wird angegriffen! Wir müssen uns vereinen, um unser Haus zu verteidigen!</string>
        <string lang="es">La ciudad está bajo ataque! ¡Debemos unirnos para defender nuestro hogar!</string>
        <string lang="pt">A cidade está sob ataque! Devemos nos unir para defender nossa casa!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_invasion_frame_2_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ah! O! EH! These revolting monsters are everywhere! One of them even devoured my Splendid Gyroscopic Magnatronic Atomizer!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ah! O! EH! Ces monstres révoltants sont partout! L'un d'entre eux a même dévoré mon magnifiques atomes Magnatronic Atomizer!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ah! O! EH! Questi mostri rivoltanti sono ovunque! Uno di loro ha anche divorato il mio Splendid Gyroscopic Magnatronic Atomizer!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ah! O! EH! Diese abscheulichen Monster sind überall! Einer von ihnen verschlang sogar meinen Splendid Gyroskopischen Magnatronic Zerstäuber!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Ah! O! EH! ¡Estos monstruos revoltosos están por todas partes! ¡Uno de ellos incluso devoró mi Splendid Gyroscopic Magnatronic Atomizer!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ah! O! EH! Esses monstros revoltantes estão em toda parte! Um deles até devorou ​​meu Splendid Gyroscopic Magnatronic Atomizer!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_invasion_frame_2_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">That magnificent name is trademarked by the way, *wink*</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ce nom magnifique est traduit par le chemin.</string>
        <string lang="it">Quel nome magnifico è marchiato dal modo.</string>
        <string lang="de">Dieser großartige Name ist von der Art und Weise markiert.</string>
        <string lang="es">Ese nombre magnífico es trademarked por el camino.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Esse nome magnífico é marca registrada, pelo caminho.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_intro_invasion_frame_4_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ahhhhhh!! They ate all of my delicious Familiar slop! It's time for all these monsters to... GO AWAY!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ahhhhhh!! Ils ont mangé tout mon slogan Familier effacé! Il est temps pour tous ces monstres de ... ALLER!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ahhhhhh!! Hanno mangiato tutti i miei delizioso Famiglio slop! È giunto il momento per tutti questi mostri di ... GO AWAY!!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ahhhhhh! Sie aßen alle meine seltsamen Schutzgeist Slop! Es ist Zeit für all diese Monster ... GO AWAY!!</string>
        <string lang="es">Ahhhhhh! ¡Comieron todo mi limo Compañero delicioso! Es hora de que todos estos monstruos ... VAYA!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ahhhhhh!! Eles comeram todo meu slogan Familiar deleçado! É hora de todos esses monstros para ... VAI AGORA!!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_raid_1_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The legend of !familiar!540!familiar! is true! We need your help to defeat the Dark Lord.</string>
        <string lang="fr">La légende de !familiar!540!familiar! est vraie ! On a besoin de ton aide pour vaincre le Seigneur des ténèbres.</string>
        <string lang="it">La leggenda !familiar!540!familiar! è realtà! Ci serve il tuo aiuto per sconfiggere l'Oscuro Signore.</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Legende von !familiar!540!familiar! ist wahr! Wir brauchen deine Hilfe, um den Dunklen Fürsten zu besiegen.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡La leyenda de !familiar!540!familiar! es cierta! Necesitamos tu ayuda para derrotar al Señor Oscuro.</string>
        <string lang="pt">A lenda de !familiar!540!familiar! é verdadeira! Precisamos da sua ajuda para derrotar o Senhor das Trevas.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_1_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Keep your eyes peeled, that realm contains very powerful loot.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ouvre l'œil, ce royaume renferme de très puissants butins.</string>
        <string lang="it">Tieni gli occhi ben aperti, in quel reame troverai parecchio bottino.</string>
        <string lang="de">Immer schön die Augen offen halten, in diesem Reich gibt es mächtige Beute.</string>
        <string lang="es">Abre bien los ojos: en el reino puedes conseguir un abundante y poderoso botín.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Fica esperto, hein: aquele reino tem uns tesouros muito poderosos.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_1_frame_4_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The Dark Caverns ain't no cake walk. You're gonna need to bring some extra help.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Les Cavernes ténébreuses ne sont pas de tout repos. Il va te falloir des renforts.</string>
        <string lang="it">Le Caverne oscure non sono un picnic. Ti servirà un po' di aiuto in più.</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Dunklen Höhlen sind kein Spaziergang. Da solltest du dich nur mit Verstärkung hineinwagen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Las Cavernas Oscuras no son ninguna broma. Vas a necesitar ayuda extra.</string>
        <string lang="pt">As Cavernas Sombrias não são moleza. É melhor você procurar uma ajudinha extra.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_2_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">EGAD! You are here, PERFECT! ... My latest invention, the BubbleOscillator, has ripped a hole into ANOTHER DIMENSION!</string>
        <string lang="fr">OUAH ! Tu es là, c'est PARFAIT !... Ma dernière invention, l'Oscillato-bulle, a ouvert une brèche vers une AUTRE DIMENSION !</string>
        <string lang="it">CRIBBIO! Sei qui, PERFETTO! La mia ultima invenzione, l'Oscillatore bollotronico, ha aperto un varco verso un'ALTRA DIMENSIONE!</string>
        <string lang="de">SIEH AN! Du bist hier, PERFEKT! ... Meine neueste Erfindung, der BlasenOszillator, hat ein Loch in eine ANDERE DIMENSION gerissen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡ANDA! ¡Estás aquí! ¡PERFECTO! ... ¡El Oscilopompa, mi nuevo invento, ha hecho un agujero que accede a OTRA DIMENSIÓN!</string>
        <string lang="pt">NOSSA SENHORA! Ainda bem que você tá aqui, PERFEITO! ... minha última invenção, o Bolhoscilador, abriu um buraco pra OUTRA DIMENSÃO!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_2_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I need you to get in there and close it before we are all *GASP*, DOOMED</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je voudrais que tu ailles la refermer avant qu'on soit tous *HOQUET*, PERDUS.</string>
        <string lang="it">Devi entrare e chiuderlo al più presto o saremo tutti *GASP* SPACCIATI!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du musst da rein und das Loch schließen, sonst sind wir alle, *JAPS*, VERLOREN!</string>
        <string lang="es">Necesito que entres y lo cierres antes de que sea el... *RESUELLO* ... FIN DE TODO.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Preciso que você feche aquilo lá antes que a gente VÁ PRO BURACO!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_3_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The Woodbeard sailed in without warning, PAY ATTENTION young hero, this story not boring!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Le Woodbeard a navigué sans avertissement, PAY ATTENTION jeune héros, cette histoire n'est pas ennuyeuse!</string>
        <string lang="it">Il Woodbeard ha navigato senza avviso, PAY ATTENZIONE giovane eroe, questa storia non noiosa!</string>
        <string lang="de">Der Woodbeard segelte ohne Vorwarnung, PAY ACHTUNG junger Held, diese Geschichte nicht langweilig!</string>
        <string lang="es">El Barba de madera navegó sin advertencia, ATENCIÓN PAYA héroe joven, esta historia no aburrido!</string>
        <string lang="pt">O Woodbeard navegou sem aviso prévio, PAY ATTENTION jovem herói, esta história não é aborrecida!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_3_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">He is here to destroy and pillage our land, with a beard made of wood and cutlass in hand.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Il est ici pour détruire et piller nos terres, avec une barbe en bois et couteaux en main.</string>
        <string lang="it">È qui per distruggere e saccheggiare la nostra terra, con una barba in legno e coltello in mano.</string>
        <string lang="de">Er ist hier, um unser Land zu zerstören und zu plündern, mit einem Bart aus Holz und Cutlass in der Hand.</string>
        <string lang="es">Él está aquí para destruir y saquear nuestra tierra, con una barba hecha de madera y un cuchillo en la mano.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ele está aqui para destruir e saquear nossa terra, com uma barba feita de madeira e talheres na mão.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_3_frame_1_content_3_desc">
        <string lang="en">Do us all a great pleasure, defeat him and loot all of his *legendary* Treasure!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Faites-nous tous un grand plaisir, battez-le et pillez tout son *legendary* Treasure!!</string>
        <string lang="it">Fai tutti un grande piacere, sconfiggi e saccheggi tutto il suo tesoro *legendary*!</string>
        <string lang="de">Haben wir alle ein großes Vergnügen, besiegen ihn und plündern alle seine *legendary* Schatz!</string>
        <string lang="es">Haznos un gran placer, derrotarlo y saquear todos sus *legendary* Treasure!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Todos nós somos um grande prazer, vencê-lo e saquear todo o *legendary* Treasure!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_4_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Oh! YOU'RE HERE!? Perfect. Ok ok ok... sooo there's a slight issue with my latest invention.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Oh! VOUS ÊTES ICI!? Parfait. Ok ok ok ... il y a donc un léger problème avec ma dernière invention.</string>
        <string lang="it">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Oh! SEI QUI!? Perfezionare. Ok ok ok ... quindi c'è un piccolo problema con la mia ultima invenzione.</string>
        <string lang="de">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Oh! DU BIST HIER!? Perfekt. Ok ok ok ... also gibt es ein kleines Problem mit meiner neuesten Erfindung.</string>
        <string lang="es">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Oh! ¿¡ESTÁS AQUÍ!? Perfecto. Ok ok ok ... entonces hay un pequeño problema con mi último invento.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Oof. Ugh! EEk!!! Ah! VOCÊ ESTÁ AQUI!? Perfeito. Ok ok ok ... então há um pequeno problema com a minha mais recente invenção.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_4_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">The Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, it ripped a hole in spacetime!! I've seen the future!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Le Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, il a déchiré un trou dans l'espace-temps !! J'ai vu le futur!</string>
        <string lang="it">Il Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, ha strappato un buco in spaceetime !! Ho visto il futuro!</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, es hat ein Loch in der Raumzeit gerissen !! Ich habe die Zukunft gesehen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, abrió un agujero en el espaciotiempo! ¡He visto el futuro!</string>
        <string lang="pt">O Wonderful TransGizmo TimeSpace O-pacitor, que rasgou um buraco no espaço-tempo !! Eu vi o futuro!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_raid_4_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">It's about your ki... I mean uh, THE FUTURE HAS BEEN TAKEN OVER BY ROMBOZ! I need you to get in there. Save the future!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">C'est à propos de vos enfants ... Je veux dire, euh, l'avenir a été pris en charge par ROMBOZ! J'ai besoin que tu y ailles. Sauve le futur !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Il suo riguardo ai tuoi figli ... intendo, il futuro è stato preso da ROMBOZ! Ho bisogno che tu entri. Salva il futuro !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Es geht um deine Kinder ... Ich meine, DIE ZUKUNFT IST ÜBER ROMBOZ ÜBERNOMMEN WORDEN! Ich brauche dich, um dorthin zu gelangen. Rette die Zukunft !!</string>
        <string lang="es">Es sobre tus hijos ... Quiero decir, ¡EL FUTURO HA SIDO TOMADO POR ROMBOZ! Necesito que entres ahí. ¡Salva el futuro!</string>
        <string lang="pt">É sobre seus filhos ... Quero dizer, uh, O FUTURO FOI TOMADO POR ROMBOZ! Preciso que você entre lá. Economize o futuro!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_shop_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ay buddy! Lookin for some new gear? I don't have much in stock at the moment. Why don't you come back in a little bit?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hé ! Tu as besoin de matériel ? Je n'ai pas grand-chose en stock pour le moment, mais reviens un peu plus tard, d'accord ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Ehilà! Cerchi equipaggiamento nuovo? Al momento sono un po' sguarnito, meglio se torni fra un po'.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ey, Alter! Suchste neue Sachen? Hab gerade nich' viel auf Lager. Komm später wieder.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Eh, colega! ¿Buscas piezas nuevas para tu equipamiento? En estos momentos ando escaso de existencias. ¿Por qué no vuelves dentro de un rato?</string>
        <string lang="pt">E aí camarada! Tá procurando equipamento? Meu estoque tá meio vazio no momento. Que tal você voltar mais tarde?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_pvp_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Hrmph... you think you're tough enough to battle in the arena? Come back when you've had a little more practice...</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hrmph... Tu te crois assez fort pour combattre dans l'arène ? Commence plutôt par t'entraîner...</string>
        <string lang="it">Uhm... Pensi di avere la stoffa per combattere nell'arena? Torna quando avrai fatto un po' più di pratica.</string>
        <string lang="de">Hrmpf ... glaubst du wirklich, du wärest stark genug, um in der Arena zu kämpfen? Komm wieder, wenn du mehr Erfahrung gesammelt hast ...</string>
        <string lang="es">Mmmm... ¿te crees lo bastante duro para combatir en el terreno de combate? Vuelve cuando hayas practicado un poco más...</string>
        <string lang="pt">Hmpf... você acha que aguenta o tranco das batalhas na arena? Melhor treinar muito antes de dar as caras por aqui...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_craft_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oy! You call that junk you're wearing 'gear'? I can make you some REAL gear!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Oh ! Qu'est-ce que c'est que cet attirail ? Je peux te fournir bien MIEUX que ça !</string>
        <string lang="it">Ohi! Quello che hai addosso me lo chiami "equipaggiamento"? Se vuoi roba VERA, posso fartela io!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ey! Nennst du den Schrott, den du da mit dir rumschleppst, etwa "Ausrüstung"? Ich kann dir eine ECHTE Ausrüstung machen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Eh! ¿Cómo puedes llamar "equipamiento" a ese trasto que llevas? ¡Yo puedo prepararte un equipo DE LOS DE VERDAD!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eita! 'Cê chama isso aí de armadura? Vem que eu te mostro o que é equipamento DE VERDADE!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_craft_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">Come back when you've found some more stuff. Maybe we can make a deal and get you really suited up!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Reviens quand tu auras récupéré plus d'objets et on essaiera de trouver un arrangement pour t'équiper correctement !</string>
        <string lang="it">Torna quando avrai trovato altra roba. Magari potremo metterci d'accordo e sistemarti per bene!</string>
        <string lang="de">Komm wieder, wenn du mehr Zeug gefunden hast. Vielleicht können wir dann einen Handel machen und dich richtig einkleiden!</string>
        <string lang="es">Vuelve cuando hayas encontrado más cosas. ¡A lo mejor podemos hacer un trato y dejarte como un pincel!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Volta aqui quando você achar mais materiais. Aí a gente pode negociar umas coisinhas pra você ficar fortão!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_fusion_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Come one, come all! Prepare ye'selves for the greatest invention of our time!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Venez, venez tous ! Préparez-vous à découvrir la plus grande invention de tous les temps !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Venghino signori venghino! Ammirate la più grande invenzione del nostro tempo!</string>
        <string lang="de">Kommet und staunet! Macht euch bereit für die größte Erfindung unserer Zeit!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Venga, venid todos! ¡¡Preparaos para el gran invento de nuestra era!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Veenham todozz, venham todozz! Se preparem pra vislumbrar a maior invenção de todoz os tempoz!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_fusion_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Beee'old!! The magic of... FUSION!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Regardez !! La magie de la... FUSION !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ammirate la magia della... FUSIONE!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich präääääsentiere! Die Magie der ... FUSION!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡Admirad!! La magia de... ¡¡LA FUSIÓN!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Observem!! A magia da... FUSÃO!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_fusion_frame_3_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">*GASP*  Ohhh... vhait...</string>
        <string lang="fr">*HOQUET* Ohhh... Attends...</string>
        <string lang="it">*GASP* Ohhh... Un momento...</string>
        <string lang="de">*JAPS* Ohhhh ... Moment ...</string>
        <string lang="es">*RESUELLO* Ohhh... ehperah...</string>
        <string lang="pt">*ENGASGA* Ixe.... calmaí...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_fusion_frame_3_content_3_desc">
        <string lang="en">I seem to have misplaced all of my schematics! If you happen to find them, bring them back to me, and I'll let you use my FUSION machine!</string>
        <string lang="fr">J'ai perdu tous mes schémas ! Si tu les trouves, rapporte-les-moi et je te laisserai utiliser ma machine à FUSION !</string>
        <string lang="it">Credo di aver perso tutti i miei progetti! Se ti capita di trovarli, riportali qui e ti farò usare la mia macchina per la FUSIONE!</string>
        <string lang="de">Offenbar habe ich alle meine Baupläne verlegt! Wenn du sie zufällig findest, bring sie mir, dann lasse ich dich meine FUSION-Maschine verwenden!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡No encuentro mis esquemas! ¡Si los ves, tráemelos y te dejaré utilizar mi máquina de FUSIÓN!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Não 'tô achando minhas fórmulas! Vixe. Faz o seguinte, se você encontrar alguma fórmula, traz pra mim e eu deixo você usar minha máquina de FUSÃO!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_mounts_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">GO AWAY!</string>
        <string lang="fr">ALLEZ, OUSTE !</string>
        <string lang="it">VIA DI QUA!</string>
        <string lang="de">GEH WEG!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡FUERA!</string>
        <string lang="pt">VAI EMBORA!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_fishing_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oi oi!! Are ye hoppin?! Th' coozin' be haur onytime noo!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hé hé! Êtes-vous excité?! Le bateau devrait être ici à tout moment maintenant !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Hey hey! Sei eccitato?! La barca dovrebbe essere qui in qualsiasi momento ora !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Hey, hey! Bist du aufgeregt?! Das Boot sollte jederzeit hier sein !!</string>
        <string lang="es">Hey hey! ¡¿Estás emocionado?! ¡El bote debería estar aquí en cualquier momento!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ei ei! Você está animado?! O barco deve estar aqui agora mesmo!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_locked_enchants_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You have brought your spoon! But alas there are no ingredients in my stew for it to go boom! Scoure the land for !enchant!1!enchant! and !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Vous avez apporté votre cuillère! Mais hélas, il n'y a pas d'ingrédients dans mon ragoût pour qu'il se lève! Score le terrain pour !enchant!1!enchant! et !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
        <string lang="it">Hai portato il tuo cucchiaio! Ma ahimé non ci sono ingredienti nel mio stufato per andare a boom! Scovare la terra per !enchant!1!enchant! e !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
        <string lang="de">Du hast deinen Löffel mitgebracht! Aber leider gibt es keine Zutaten in meinem Eintopf für es zu gehen Boom! Scoure das Land für !enchant!1!enchant! und !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Has traído tu cuchara! Pero por desgracia no hay ingredientes en mi guiso para que vaya boom! Scoure la tierra para !enchant!1!enchant! y !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você trouxe sua colher! Mas, infelizmente, não há ingredientes no meu ensopado para que ele vá boom! Score a terra para !enchant!1!enchant! e !enchant!10!enchant!.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_enchants_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">Don't be a fool, even an !enchant!7!enchant! could be on these roads.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ne soyez pas fou, même un !enchant!7!enchant! pourrait être sur ces routes.</string>
        <string lang="it">Non essere uno stupido, anche una !enchant!7!enchant! potrebbe essere su queste strade.</string>
        <string lang="de">Sei nicht ein Narr, auch ein !enchant!7!enchant! könnte auf diesen Straßen sein.</string>
        <string lang="es">No seas un tonto, incluso un !enchant!7!enchant! podría estar en estas carreteras.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Não seja um tolo, mesmo um !enchant!7!enchant! poderia estar nessas estradas.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_enchants_frame_1_content_3_desc">
        <string lang="en">A !enchant!16!enchant! and a !enchant!20!enchant! are also very rare, but if you can find them you will become stronger, if you dare!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Un !enchant!16!enchant! et un !enchant!20!enchant! sont également très rares, mais si vous pouvez les trouver, vous deviendrez plus fort, si vous osez!</string>
        <string lang="it">Un !enchant!16!enchant! e un !enchant!20!enchant! sono anche molto rari, ma se li puoi trovare, diventerai più forte, se oseri!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ein !enchant!16!enchant! und ein !enchant!20!enchant! sind auch sehr selten, aber wenn du sie finden kannst, wirst du stärker werden, wenn du es wagst!</string>
        <string lang="es">Un !enchant!16!enchant! y un !enchant!20!enchant! son también muy raros, pero si usted puede encontrarlos usted llegará a ser más fuerte, si usted se atreve!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Um !enchant!16!enchant! e um !enchant!20!enchant! também são muito raros, mas se você pode encontrá-los, você se tornará mais forte, se você se atreve!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_locked_rifts_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Puny little hero, don't bother me until you're stronger.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Reviens me voir quand tu seras plus fort, petit héros de pacotille.</string>
        <string lang="it">Piccolo, gracile eroe, non venire a seccarmi finché non sarai più forte.</string>
        <string lang="de">Jämmerlicher kleiner Held, belästige mich nicht, bis du stärker bist.</string>
        <string lang="es">Pequeño héroe enclenque... No me molestes hasta que tengas más fuerza.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Heroizinho de meia tigela, vê se cresce depois vem falar comigo.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_locked_gauntlet_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Yah, you look kinda vhimpy! Maybe come back vhen you are a wittle strongah, yah?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu n'as pas l'air bien vigoureux ! Reviens me voir quand tu seras un peu plus fort, d'accord ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Zembri un poko deboluccio! Forze tu torni kvando sei un poko più forzuto, ja?</string>
        <string lang="de">Ja, du siehst voll schwach aus! Komm halt wieder, wenn du stärker bist, ey!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Vaya, tienes pinta de llorón! Ozú, vuerve cuando seah un poco máh fuerte, ¿capiche?</string>
        <string lang="pt">É mermo, 'cê é meio fracote! Tenta ficá mais fortaum pra vir aqui, belê?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_goblin_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Marglhualurg urga burgla marguhrughg...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r1_goblin_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Orga burxa murgaburgh blarga argabargh!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r1_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ignorant fool! You think you can defeat ME!?!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Imbécile heureux ! Tu crois pouvoir ME battre !?!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ebete incapace! Credi di poter sconfiggere ME?</string>
        <string lang="de">Ignoranter Narr! Du glaubst, du kannst MICH besiegen?!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Estúpido ignorante! ¡¿¡Crees que puedes derrotarme!?!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Pentelho imprudente! Acha MESMO que pode me enfrentar!?!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r1_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The power of darkness will consume your soul!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Les forces des ténèbres vont consumer ton âme !</string>
        <string lang="it">Il potere delle tenebre banchetterà con la tua anima!</string>
        <string lang="de">Die Macht der Dunkelheit wird deine Seele verzehren!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡El poder de las tinieblas consumirá tu alma!</string>
        <string lang="pt">O poder das trevas tomará conta da sua alma!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n1_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Me Tubbo! Me smash yo face!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Moi Tubbo ! Moi te fracasser l'crâne !</string>
        <string lang="it">Me Tubbo! Me spacca faccia di te!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich Tubbo! Ich dir Fresse polieren!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Yo Tubbo! ¡Yo aplastar tu cara!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sô o Tubbo! I vô quebrá sua cara!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n2_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">ooOoOooooOo Oo oooo...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n2_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">OOOOOOOO OO OOOOO OOOOO!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Not even death can save you from me!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Même mort, tu ne m'échapperas pas !</string>
        <string lang="it">Nemmeno la morte può salvarti da me!</string>
        <string lang="de">Nicht einmal der Tod kann dich vor mir retten!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Ni la muerte puede salvarte de mis garras!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Nem a morte pode salvar você dos meus poderes!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n6_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Who dares go stompin through OUR forest!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Qui ose pénétrer dans NOTRE forêt !?</string>
        <string lang="it">Chi osa calpestare la NOSTRA foresta?!</string>
        <string lang="de">Wer wagt es, durch UNSEREN Wald zu stampfen?!</string>
        <string lang="es">¿¡Quién osa pisotear NUESTRO bosque!?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Quem ousa plantar os pés na NOSSA floresta!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n6_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You better make like tree and get outta here!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu ferais mieux de décamper !</string>
        <string lang="it">Vedi di andartene prima che io mi inalberi!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du trägst zwar keinen Frack, aber mach die Fliege!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Más te vale largarte sin andarte por las ramas!</string>
        <string lang="pt">É melhor cê dar no pé de bananeira daqui agora mesmo!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I'm the spirit of the forest. You have unsettled our land. Prepare for battle!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis l'esprit de la forêt. Puisque tu as troublé la quiétude de notre royaume, prépare-toi à te battre !</string>
        <string lang="it">Sono lo spirito della foresta. Hai disturbato le nostre terre. Preparati alla battaglia!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin der Geist des Waldes. Du hast unser Land gestört. Rüste dich zum Kampf!</string>
        <string lang="es">Yo soy el espíritu de este bosque. Has desestabilizado nuestra tierra. ¡Prepárate para la batalla!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou o espírito da floresta. Você perturbou a nossa terra. Prepare-se para a batalha!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n10_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Urm.. uh.. huh... WHAT!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hum... Euh... QUOI !?</string>
        <string lang="it">Urm.. Uh.. Uhm... COSA?!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ähm ... äh ... hm ... WAS?!</string>
        <string lang="es">Mmm.. oh.. eh... ¿¡QUÉ!?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Erm... hm... hmmm... QUÊ!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z1_n12_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">!!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n1_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Pukko...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n1_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">PUKKO!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n2_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">GOBBLE wheres my argyle GOBBLE sweater at!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">GLOUGLOU, où est mon chandail à losanges, GLOUGLOU !?</string>
        <string lang="it">GOBBLE dov'è il mio GOBBLE maglione di lana?!</string>
        <string lang="de">TRUT wo ist mein TRUT Argyle-Pullover?!</string>
        <string lang="es">GLUP. ¿¡Dónde está mi suéter GLUP de rombos!?</string>
        <string lang="pt">GLUGLU cadê o meu casaco de GLUGLU tricô!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n2_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">GOBBLE!!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">GLOUGLOU !!!</string>
        <string lang="it">GOBBLE!</string>
        <string lang="de">TRUT!!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡¡GLUP!!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">GLUGLU!!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n3_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Pukko PUKKO!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n3_boss_frame_2_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Yeah! What he said! GOBBLE GOBBLE!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ouais ! C'est ce qu'il a dit ! GLOUGLOU GLOUGLOU !!!</string>
        <string lang="it">Sì! Come ha detto lui! GOBBLE GOBBLE!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ja! Genau! TRUT TRUT!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Sí! ¡Lo que ha dicho él! ¡¡GLUP GLUP!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">É isso aí mesmo que ele falou! GLUGLU GLUGLU!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Hey! Who's this ICE hole?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hé ! C'est qui cette bique à GLACE ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Ehi! Chi è questa testa di GHIACCIO?</string>
        <string lang="de">Hey! Wo ist dieses EISloch?</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Eh! ¿Quién es este desgracielado?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Opa! Quem é esse PICOLÉ DE CHUCHU aí?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n4_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You better chill out! This Yeti is cooler than frozen Spaghetti!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Relax ! Y'a pas plus cool que ce Yeti !</string>
        <string lang="it">Calma e sangue freddo! Questo Yeti è più gelido di un surgelato!</string>
        <string lang="de">Schön cool bleiben! Der Yeti hier ist cooler als gefrorene Spaghetti!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Calma, chocolate frío, échalo al río! ¡Este Yeti está más frío que un espagueti congelado!</string>
        <string lang="pt">É melhor esfriar a cabeça! Sou um Ieti mais frio que artilheiro na final!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n6_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You think you can wander around in my sewers? I don't think so!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Qui t'a autorisé à entrer dans mes égouts ? Pas moi, en tout cas !</string>
        <string lang="it">Credi di poter andare a zonzo per le mie fogne? Io credo di no!</string>
        <string lang="de">Glaubst du, du kannst einfach so in meiner Kanalisation herumspazieren? Falsch geglaubt!</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Crees que puedes andar a tus anchas por mis cloacas? ¡Pues va a ser que no!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você acha que pode vir entrando assim no meu esgoto? Ah mas 'cê vai ver só!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You look tasty. I think I just found my dinner!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu es bien appétissant, dis-moi. Je sens que je vais me régaler !</string>
        <string lang="it">Hai l'aria appetitosa. È appena arrivata la cena!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du siehst lecker aus. Ich glaube, ich habe gerade mein Abendessen gefunden!</string>
        <string lang="es">Tienes pinta de saber a gloria. ¡Creo que acabo de encontrar la cena!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você parece apetitoso. Acho que já sei o que vai ter na janta!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n9_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You think you've got what it takes to battle me? Try 3 of me!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu te crois à la hauteur contre moi ? Attends un peu qu'on soit 3 face à toi !</string>
        <string lang="it">Credi di avere la stoffa per affrontarmi? Vediamo cosa fai se siamo in tre!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du hältst dich für stark genug, mich zu bekämpfen? Wie wär's mit dreimal mir?</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Crees que tienes lo que hay que tener para enfrentarte a mí? ¡Prueba con 3 como yo!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você acha que aguenta um duelo contra mim? E contra 3 de mim!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n11_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Halt!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Halte-là !</string>
        <string lang="it">Altolà!</string>
        <string lang="de">Halt!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Alto!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Parado!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n11_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Got a wise mouth here eh?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu as la langue bien pendue, dis-moi !</string>
        <string lang="it">Abbiamo la lingua sciolta, eh?</string>
        <string lang="de">Ah, ein kleines Großmaul, was?</string>
        <string lang="es">Veo que tienes la lengua muy larga, ¿eh?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Falastrão esse aí hein?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n11_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I've had enough of your attitude!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ton attitude commence à me taper sur les nerfs !</string>
        <string lang="it">Ne ho avuto abbastanza di te!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich habe genug von deinem Getue!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Pues ya me he hartado de tu fanfarronería!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Já cansei dessa sua audácia!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n12_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ahhhh! Check out my pecks!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ahhhh ! Mate un peu mes coups de bec !</string>
        <string lang="it">Aah! Guarda che pettorali!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ahhhh! Zieh dir meine Pectoralis rein!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Uuuuy! ¡Mira mis pectorales!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Tá saindo da jaula o monstro!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n12_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Well... what about these deltz?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Alors... que dis-tu de ces deltz ?</string>
        <string lang="it">E che ne dici di questi deltoidi?</string>
        <string lang="de">Tja ... was ist mit diesen Deltoiden?</string>
        <string lang="es">Bueno... ¿y qué me dices de estos hombros?</string>
        <string lang="pt">O que achou do meu trapézio descendente?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z2_n12_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Alright then... welcome to the gun show!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Bien... bienvenue à l'expo d'armes à feu !</string>
        <string lang="it">E va bene, beccati il pezzo forte!</string>
        <string lang="de">Alles klar ... willkommen zur Waffenshow!</string>
        <string lang="es">Adelante... ¡Bienvenido al espectáculo de armas!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Então é hora do show, pô!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n2_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">DINA DINA DINA DINA DINA!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Mwaahahahaha! Prepare for your doo.. doom!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Mouaahahahaha ! Prépare-toi à mour... mourir !</string>
        <string lang="it">Muah ah ah! Preparati alla mo... morte!</string>
        <string lang="de">Mwaahahahaha! Mach dich bereit für deinen Unterg– ... Untergang!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Uajajajajajaja! ¡Prepárate para tu fi... final!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Mwahahahahah! Prepare-se para o seu fi... fim!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n5_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">... gurrrrgle ...</string>
        <string lang="fr">... gargouillis...</string>
        <string lang="it">...gurrrgle...</string>
        <string lang="de">... gurgel ...</string>
        <string lang="es">... glu glu ...</string>
        <string lang="pt">... gluglu ...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n5_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">... BARF!</string>
        <string lang="fr">... VOMI !</string>
        <string lang="it">...BLEAH!</string>
        <string lang="de">... SPUCK!</string>
        <string lang="es">... ¡POTA!</string>
        <string lang="pt">... RAUL!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n6_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">The ancient prophecy fortold of your arrival...</string>
        <string lang="fr">La prophétie ancienne avait prédit ton arrivée...</string>
        <string lang="it">L'antica profezia aveva annunciato il tuo arrivo...</string>
        <string lang="de">Die alte Prophezeiung hat deine Ankunft vorhergesagt ...</string>
        <string lang="es">La profecía ancestral predijo tu llegada...</string>
        <string lang="pt">A antiga profecia anunciou a tua chegada...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">*tck* *tck* *tck* *tck*</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n9_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I am the sword in the darkness, and the shield that guards this castle.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis l'épée des ténèbres et le bouclier qui protège ce château.</string>
        <string lang="it">Io sono la spada nelle tenebre, lo scudo che veglia su questo castello.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin das Schwert in der Dunkelheit und der Schild, der dieses Schloss bewacht.</string>
        <string lang="es">Yo soy la espada en las tinieblas y el escudo que protege este castillo.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou a espada na escuridão, o escudo que protege este castelo.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n10_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">My bones ache, and your bones will break!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Mes os me font mal et les tiens vont être pulvérisés !</string>
        <string lang="it">Le mie ossa scricchiolano, le tue si spezzeranno!</string>
        <string lang="de">Meine Knochen ächzen, deine werden brechen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Mis huesos crujen y los tuyos se partirán!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Meus ossos doem, e os seus ossos irão rachar no meio!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z3_n12_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I am the evil that protects this castle. The shadows betray you because they serve me.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis le mal qui protège ce château. Les ombres te trahissent parce qu'elles sont à mon service.</string>
        <string lang="it">Io sono il male che protegge questo castello. Le ombre ti tradiscono, poiché servono me.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin das Böse, das dieses Schloss bewacht. Die Schatten verraten dich, weil sie mir dienen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Yo soy el ser maléfico que protege este castillo. Las sombras te traicionan porque están a mi servicio.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou o mal que protege este castelo. As sombras te denunciam, afinal elas estão à meu serviço.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n1_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ooga chaka ooga chaka.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n1_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Jugga wugga ooga chaka!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n1_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">CHOOGA WUGGA OOGA CHAKA!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n2_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">KA KAW!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oh dear, I've never had my meal approach me before.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Oh, c'est la première fois que mon repas vient à moi.</string>
        <string lang="it">Oh santo cielo, non è mai successo che la cena arrivasse da sola.</string>
        <string lang="de">Oh weh, ich wurde noch nie von meinem Essen angesprochen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Oh, vaya, nunca antes se me había acercado la cena.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ah, jovem, esta é a primeira vez que minha refeição fala comigo.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n4_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Come a little closer my tasty friend!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Approche-toi, appétissant ami !</string>
        <string lang="it">Avvicinati un po' di più, bel bocconcino!</string>
        <string lang="de">Komm näher, mein leckerer kleiner Freund!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Ven un poco más cerca, manjar exquisito!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Aproxime-se, criatura apetitosa!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n6_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">MYYAAHHHH! Cool lookin' gear you got there! Whered you get it?</string>
        <string lang="fr">OUAAHHHH ! Sacré matos ! Où l'as-tu dégoté ?</string>
        <string lang="it">YAAH! Ehi, hai della gran bella roba! Dove l'hai presa?</string>
        <string lang="de">MYYAAHHHH! Coole Ausrüstung hast du da! Wo ist die her??</string>
        <string lang="es">¡ALUCINEEE! ¡Menudo equipamiento lleva el maniquí! ¿De dónde lo has sacado?</string>
        <string lang="pt">RÁÁÁÁÁÁ! Que equipamentos irados esses seus! Onde 'cê conseguiu?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n6_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Not gonna tell me eh? After I give you the smackdown you'll have to tell me!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu ne veux rien me dire ? Peu importe, je finirai par te faire parler !</string>
        <string lang="it">Non vuoi dirmelo, eh? Beh, quando ti avrò pestato per bene, me lo dirai per forza!</string>
        <string lang="de">Willst es mir nicht sagen, was? Wenn ich mit dir fertig bin, musst du es mir sagen!</string>
        <string lang="es">No me lo vas a decir, ¿verdad? ¡Cuando te haya dado una buena paliza, tendrás que decírmelo!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Não vai contar né? Então deixa que eu arranco da tua boca à força!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n6_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">MYYYAAAAAHHHHHH!!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">*ribbit* wanna hear a joke?</string>
        <string lang="fr">*croa croa*, tu veux que je te raconte une blague ?</string>
        <string lang="it">*cra cra* Vuoi sentire una storiella?</string>
        <string lang="de">*quak* Willst du einen Witz hören?</string>
        <string lang="es">*croac* ¿Te cuento un chiste?</string>
        <string lang="pt">*croc croc* quer ouvir uma piada?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n8_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Why didn't the bit hero cross my sewers?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Pourquoi le petit héros n'a-t-il pas traversé mes égouts ?</string>
        <string lang="it">Perché l'eroe non attraversa le mie fogne?</string>
        <string lang="de">Warum ist der Bit Hero nicht durch meine Kanalisation gekommen?</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Por qué el bit hero no cruzó mi cloaca?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Por que o bit-herói NÃO atravessou o meu esgoto?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n8_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">BECAUSE I ATE EM!</string>
        <string lang="fr">PARCE QUE JE L'AI MANGÉ !</string>
        <string lang="it">PERCHÉ LO MANGIO PRIMA!</string>
        <string lang="de">WEIL ICH IHN GEFRESSEN HABE!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡PORQUE ME LO TRAGUÉ!</string>
        <string lang="pt">PORQUE EU ENGOLI ELE!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n10_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oh! A ball! Oh boy, oh boy a ball! I have just met you and I love you!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Oh ! Un ballon ! Youpi ! On vient à peine de se rencontrer, mais tu me plais déjà beaucoup !</string>
        <string lang="it">Oh! Una pallina! Che bello, che bello, una pallina! Ti ho appena incontrato e ti voglio già bene!</string>
        <string lang="de">Oh! Ein Ball! Oh Junge, oh Junge, ein Ball! Ich hab dich gerade erst kennengelernt und ich liebe dich!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Oh! ¡Una pelota! ¡Madre mía, una pelota! ¡Acabo de conocerte y ya te adoro!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Opa! Uma bola! Ai minhanossa, uma bola! Acabei de te conhecer e já te considero pacas!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n10_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You won't throw the ball?... *growls* I have just met you... and now I'll EAT YOU.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu ne veux pas lancer le ballon ?... *grognements* On vient à peine de se rencontrer... et je vais déjà devoir TE MANGER.</string>
        <string lang="it">Non mi lanci la pallina? *grrr* Ti ho appena incontrato... e ti voglio già MANGIARE!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du wirfst den Ball nicht? ... *knurr* Ich hab dich gerade erst kennengelernt ... und jetzt FRESSE ICH DICH!</string>
        <string lang="es">¿No vas a lanzar la pelota? *gruñe* Acabo de conocerte... y voy a COMERTE.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você não vai jogar bola?... *grunhe* Eu acabei de te conhecer... e agora vou TE ENGOLIR!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n12_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Mmmmm. What might we have here? A new little hero? You are an adorable one.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Mmmmm. Qu'est-ce qu'on a là ? Un nouveau petit héros ? Comme il est mignon !</string>
        <string lang="it">Uhmmm. Che cos'abbiamo qui? Un nuovo piccolo eroe? Ma sei adorabile!</string>
        <string lang="de">Mmmmm. Was haben wir denn hier? Einen neuen kleinen Helden? Du bist vielleicht niedlich.</string>
        <string lang="es">Mmmmm. ¿Qué tenemos por aquí? ¿Un nuevo héroe de pacotilla? Qué ricura.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Hmmmmm. O que é isso aqui? Um novo heroizinho? Que coisa mais bonitinha.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z4_n12_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Come closer my dear, I want to get a good look at you.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Approche-toi, laisse-moi te regarder.</string>
        <string lang="it">Vieni più vicino, voglio vederti bene.</string>
        <string lang="de">Komm näher, mein Lieber, ich will dich genauer ansehen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Acércate, encanto, quiero mirarte y remirarte.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Chega perto benzinho pra eu poder te ver melhor.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n3_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Bebemenz!! Bebemenz!! Huehuehuehue</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Meep. Meep. Meep. MEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEP. Meep. Meep. Meep</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n7_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">HEY SKINDIANA BONES! Dont be jealous that I'm shredded like lettuce.</string>
        <string lang="fr">HEY SKINDIANA BONES! Ne soyez pas jaloux que je suis déchiqueté comme la laitue.</string>
        <string lang="it">HEY SKINDIANA BONES! Non essere geloso di essere tagliato come lattuga.</string>
        <string lang="de">HEY SKINDIANA BONES! Sei nicht eifersüchtig, dass ich wie Salat zerrissen bin.</string>
        <string lang="es">HOLA SKINDIANA BONES! No seas celoso que estoy triturado como lechuga.</string>
        <string lang="pt">EI SKINDIANA BONES! Não fique com ciúmes que estou morrendo de alface.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n7_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">!familiar!240!familiar! got nuffin on me! Check out my OWLBLIQUES!</string>
        <string lang="fr">!familiar!240!familiar! n'a rien sur moi! Regardez mes OBLIQUES!</string>
        <string lang="it">!familiar!240!familiar! non ha nulla su di me! Guarda i miei OBLIQUI!</string>
        <string lang="de">!familiar!240!familiar! hat nichts an mir! Schauen Sie sich meine OBLIQUES!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡!familiar!240!familiar! no tiene nada conmigo! Echa un vistazo a mis OBLICUOS!</string>
        <string lang="pt">!familiar!240!familiar! não conseguiu nada em mim! Confira os meus OBLÍQUOS!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I am the Calamity of Winter!! I will chill you to your bones.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis la Calamité de l'hiver !! Je vais vous rafraîchir à vos os.</string>
        <string lang="it">Sono la Calamità dell'inverno !! Ti farò gelare alle tue ossa.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin das Unglück des Winters !! Ich werde dich zu deinen Knochen kühlen.</string>
        <string lang="es">Yo soy la Calamidad de invierno! Te enfriaré a tus huesos.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou a Calamidade do inverno! Eu vou relaxar você até seus ossos.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n11_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I cant see my toes!? I CANT SEE MY TOES!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je ne peux pas voir mes orteils !? JE VEUX VOIR TOUS TOUS!</string>
        <string lang="it">Non riesco a vedere le dita dei piedi !? CANT VEDERE I MIEI TOES !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich kann meine Zehen nicht sehen !? ICH KANN MEINE ZEHEN SEHEN !!</string>
        <string lang="es">No puedo ver mis dedos de los pies !? ¡NO PUEDO VER LOS PIES !!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu não posso ver meus dedos do pé !? Eu posso ver meus dedos!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n12_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Wook into my Mind Contrwol stwaff... you are getting shweepy... wery wery shweeeeeepppyyy</string>
        <string lang="fr">Regardez dans mon personnel de Mind Control ... vous avez sommeil ... très très endormi</string>
        <string lang="it">Guarda nel mio staff del Controllo della Mente ... tu stai dormendo ... molto stanco</string>
        <string lang="de">Schau in meine Mind Control Personal ... du wirst schläfrig ... sehr sehr schläfrig</string>
        <string lang="es">Mire en mi personal de control mental ... usted está consiguiendo sueño ... muy muy soñoliento</string>
        <string lang="pt">Olhe para a minha equipe de controle da mente ... você está com sono ... muito, muito com sono</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z5_n12_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">BAH! I shwouldn't have swaid it was a Mind Contwol stwaff!! ...ATWACK!</string>
        <string lang="fr">BAH! Je n'aurais pas dû dire que c'était un personnel de Mind Control !! ...ATTAQUE!</string>
        <string lang="it">BAH! Non avrei dovuto dire che era un personale di controllo della mente !! ...ATTACCO!</string>
        <string lang="de">BAH! Ich hätte nicht sagen können, dass es ein Mind Control Personal war! ...ATTACKE!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡BAH! No debería haber dicho que era un personal de control de la mente !! ...¡ATAQUE!</string>
        <string lang="pt">BAH! Eu não deveria ter dito que era uma equipe do Mind Control !! ...ATAQUE!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n3_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">My name is !familiar!2220!familiar!! Isn't that just neat-O! Look at my robe it has no sleave-Os!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je m'appelle !familiar!2220!familiar!! N'est-ce pas juste-O! Regarde ma robe elle n'a pas de sleave-Os!</string>
        <string lang="it">Mi chiamo !familiar!2220!familiar!! Non è così semplice! Guarda la mia abito che non ha niente-os!</string>
        <string lang="de">Mein Name ist !familiar!2220!familiar!! Ist das nicht nur ordentlich - O! Sieh dir meine Robe an, sie hat keine Sleave-Os!</string>
        <string lang="es">Mi nombre es !familiar!2220!familiar!! ¿No es eso simplemente bueno? ¡O! Mira mi túnica, no tiene nada, ¡Os!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Meu nome é !familiar!2220!familiar!! Não é só isso, puro! Olhe para o meu manto, não tem nenhuma onda.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You wanna know how I got these rolls!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu veux savoir comment j'ai eu ces rouleaux?</string>
        <string lang="it">Vuoi sapere come ho ottenuto questi rotoli ?!</string>
        <string lang="de">Willst du wissen, wie ich diese Brötchen bekommen habe?</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Quieres saber cómo conseguí estos rollos?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você quer saber como consegui esses roquetes !?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n4_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Well... it's probably cuz I eat everyone who enters my sewer!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Eh bien ... c'est probablement parce que je mange tout le monde qui entre dans mon égout !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Beh ... probabilmente cuz mangiare tutti coloro che entrano nella mia fogna !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Nun ... es ist wahrscheinlich weil ich jeden esse, der meinen Abwasserkanal betritt !!</string>
        <string lang="es">Bueno ... es probable porque yo como todos los que entran en mi alcantarilla.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Bem ... provavelmente é porque eu como todos os que entram no meu esgoto !!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n5_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Om chom, Om chom, Om chom. Weooop!! Om chom, Om chom, Om chom. Weooop!! Ommmmm Chom chom.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n6_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">My music is the grandest in all the land!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ma musique est la plus grande de toute la terre !!</string>
        <string lang="it">La mia musica è la più grande in tutta la terra !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Meine Musik ist die großartigste im ganzen Land !!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Mi música es la más grandiosa de toda la tierra!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Minha música é a melhor em toda a terra!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n6_boss_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">I've been called the flutebird of my generation by people who have heard me flute.</string>
        <string lang="fr">J'ai été appelé le flutebird de ma génération par des gens qui m'ont entendu flûte.</string>
        <string lang="it">Sono stato chiamato il flauto della mia generazione da parte di persone che mi hanno sentito flauto.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich wurde von Leuten, die mich Flöte gehört haben, der Flötenvogel meiner Generation genannt.</string>
        <string lang="es">Me han llamado el pájaro flauta de mi generación por personas que me han escuchado la flauta.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu fui chamado o flutebird da minha geração por pessoas que me ouviram flauta.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n7_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">CHOMP CHOMP CHOMP CHOMP</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n8_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">OOOO. TINY. LITTLE. SMALL. ITTYBITTY. SNACK!</string>
        <string lang="fr">OOOO. MINUSCULE. PEU. PETIT. ITTY BITTY. CASSE-CROÛTE!</string>
        <string lang="it">OOOO. TINY. PICCOLO. GIOVANE. MERENDA!</string>
        <string lang="de">OOOO. SEHR KLEIN. WENIG. KLEIN. ITTY BITTY. SNACK!</string>
        <string lang="es">OOOO. MINÚSCULO. PEQUEÑO. PEQUEÑA. ITTY BITTY. ¡BOCADILLO!</string>
        <string lang="pt">OOOO. MINÚSCULO. PEQUENO. PEQUENO. BATENTE DE IDIOMA. SNACK!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n11_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Your death will be by my hand!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Votre mort sera par ma main!</string>
        <string lang="it">La tua morte sarà per mia mano!</string>
        <string lang="de">Dein Tod wird durch meine Hand sein!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Tu muerte será por mi mano!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Sua morte estará por minha mão!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_z6_n12_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Your silence proves you are scared!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ton silence prouve que tu as peur!</string>
        <string lang="it">Il tuo silenzio dimostra che sei spaventato!</string>
        <string lang="de">Dein Schweigen beweist, dass du Angst hast!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Tu silencio demuestra que tienes miedo!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Seu silêncio prova que você está com medo!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_goblin_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Hehehe, this treasure is mine!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hé hé hé, ce trésor est à moi !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Eh eh eh, il tesoro è mio!</string>
        <string lang="de">Hehehe, dieser Schatz gehört mir!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡Jejeje, este tesoro es mío!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Hehehe, o tesouro é meu!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I am KALEIDOOOOOOOO! The guardian of this dimension!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis KALEIDOOOOOOOO, le gardien de cette dimension !</string>
        <string lang="it">Io sono KALEIDOOO! Il guardiano di questa dimensione!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin KALEIDOOOOOOOO! Der Wächter dieser Dimension!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Soy KALEIDOOOOOOOO! ¡El guardián de esta dimensión!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou KALEIDOOOOOOOO! O guardião desta dimensão!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">No puny mortal has ever dared to step foot in my dimension before. Your power is truly impressive!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Aucun mortel n'avait encore jamais osé s'aventurer dans ma dimension. Tu es très impressionnant !</string>
        <string lang="it">Nessun misero mortale ha mai osato metter piede nella mia dimensione prima d'ora. Il tuo potere è davvero notevole!</string>
        <string lang="de">Kein jämmerlicher Sterblicher hat es je zuvor gewagt, einen Fuß in meine Dimension zu setzen. Deine Macht ist wahrlich beeindruckend!</string>
        <string lang="es">Ningún insignificante mortal había osado antes entrar en mi dimensión. ¡Tu poder es algo impresionante!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Nenhum frágil mortal jamais ousou entrar na minha dimensão. Seu poder é muito impressionante!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r2_boss_frame_5_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">FINALLY!! A true challenge awaits me.</string>
        <string lang="fr">ENFIN un vrai défi !!</string>
        <string lang="it">FINALMENTE! Mi si presenta una vera sfida.</string>
        <string lang="de">ENDLICH!!! Eine echte Herausforderung erwartet mich.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡POR FIN!! Me espera un desafío real.</string>
        <string lang="pt">FINALMENTE! Um desafio de verdade para mim.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r3_goblin_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">BLIMEY!</string>
        <string lang="fr">BLIMEY!</string>
        <string lang="it">BLIMEY!</string>
        <string lang="de">BLIMEY!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡CARAY!</string>
        <string lang="pt">CARAMBA!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r3_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Well shave me belly with a rusty razor! Who is this skallywag who has stumbled on my galleon?</string>
        <string lang="fr">Bien raser le ventre avec un rasoir rouillé! Qui est ce skallywag qui a trébuché sur mon galion?</string>
        <string lang="it">Mi spara bene la pancia con un rasoio arrugginito! Chi è questo skallywag che si è imbattuto sul mio galeone?</string>
        <string lang="de">Gut rasieren Sie mir Bauch mit einem rostigen Rasiermesser! Wer ist dieser Skallywag, der auf meine Galeone gestoßen ist?</string>
        <string lang="es">Bueno, afeitarme el vientre con una maquinilla de afeitar oxidada! ¿Quién es este skallywag que ha tropezado con mi galeón?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Bem me raspe a barriga com uma lâmina enferrujada! Quem é esse skallywag que tropeçou no meu galeão?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r3_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Shiver me timbers! Ye be covered in booty that belong to me! Avast ye! Prepare to dance the hempen jig!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Bien raser le ventre avec un rasoir rouillé! Qui est ce skallywag qui a trébuché sur mon galion?</string>
        <string lang="it">Mi spara bene la pancia con un rasoio arrugginito! Chi è questo skallywag che si è imbattuto sul mio galeone?</string>
        <string lang="de">Gut rasieren Sie mir Bauch mit einem rostigen Rasiermesser! Wer ist dieser Skallywag, der auf meine Galeone gestoßen ist?</string>
        <string lang="es">Bueno, afeitarme el vientre con una maquinilla de afeitar oxidada! ¿Quién es este skallywag que ha tropezado con mi galeón?</string>
        <string lang="pt">Bem me raspe a barriga com uma lâmina enferrujada! Quem é esse skallywag que tropeçou no meu galeão?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r4_goblin_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">beep... beep... beep... beep...</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r4_boss_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">urrrr EEEE urrr NNNGGGG CRRRRcrrrr KEEEEEEE grrr nnnnnng</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_r4_boss_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">EEEERRRKKKKKK URRRRRRR KEEERRRCCHHHHHHHZZZZZ GRRR NNNNNGG</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    
    <!-- Halloween -->
    
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_craft_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Happy Halloween Hero! Here, you can have my extra inflatable Sumo Suit! TWINSIES!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Joyeux héros d'Halloween! Ici, vous pouvez avoir ma combinaison de sumo gonflable supplémentaire! JUMEAUX!</string>
        <string lang="it">Felice Halloween Hero! Qui potete avere il mio extra Sumo Suit gonfiabile! GEMELLI!</string>
        <string lang="de">Fröhlicher Halloween-Held! Hier kannst du meinen extra aufblasbaren Sumo-Anzug haben! ZWILLINGE!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Feliz Halloween Hero! ¡Aquí puedes tener mi traje de sumo inflable extra! ¡GEMELOS!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Feliz herói do Dia das Bruxas! Aqui, você pode ter o meu sutiã inflável extra Sumo! GÊMEOS!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_leaderboard_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">RRAAa raAAaAaaA rAaA araaaa Ooooo RAAA rraAAA!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_pvp_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">What am I!? I am a cat, duh</string>
        <string lang="fr">Que suis je!? Je suis un chat, duh</string>
        <string lang="it">Cosa sono!? Sono un gatto, spirito</string>
        <string lang="de">Was bin ich!? Ich bin eine Katze, duh</string>
        <string lang="es">¿¡Qué soy yo!? Soy un gato, duh</string>
        <string lang="pt">O que eu sou!? Eu sou um gato, duh</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_quest_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">You're never gonna guess what I am for Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Tu ne devineras jamais ce que je suis pour Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="it">Non ti indovina mai quello che sto per Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="de">Du wirst nie erraten, was ich für Halloween bin!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Nunca vas a adivinar lo que soy para Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Você nunca vai adivinhar o que sou para Halloween!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_quest_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Im'a slice of pizza!! I've been foolin' everyone!! Happy Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je suis une tranche de pizza !! J'ai trompé 'tout le monde !! Joyeux Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="it">Sono una fetta di pizza !! Ho scioccato tutti! Felice Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich bin ein Stück Pizza !! Ich habe alle 'getäuscht' !! Fröhliches Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Soy una rebanada de pizza! ¡He estado engañando a todos! ¡Feliz Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Eu sou uma fatia de pizza !! Eu estive enganando 'todos !! Feliz Dia das Bruxas!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_shop_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ah, it's like my golden years all over again! I bet you I can still JAMalamadingdong and make swoosh! Happy Halloween!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ah, c'est comme mes années d'or encore une fois! Je vous parie que je peux encore JAMalamadingdong et faire swoosh! Joyeux Halloween!!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ah, è come i miei anni d'oro di nuovo! Scommetto che posso ancora JAMalamadingdong e fare swoosh! Felice Halloween!!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ah, es ist wieder wie meine goldenen Jahre! Ich wette du kannst ich noch JAMalamadingdong und swoosh machen! Fröhliches Halloween!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Ah, es como mis años dorados otra vez! ¡Apuesto que aún puedo JAMalamadingdong y make swoosh! ¡¡Feliz Halloween!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ah, é como meus anos dourados de novo! Eu aposto que você ainda pode JAMalamadingdong e fazer swoosh! Feliz Dia das Bruxas!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_fusion_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">OO, AH! Hey! OH my! Perfect time to test out my Incredible Transvampcapasitor Voicemodulator. Ready!?</string>
        <string lang="fr">OO, AH! Hey! Oh mon! Le moment parfait pour tester mon incroyable Voicemodulator Transvampcapasitor. Prêt!?</string>
        <string lang="it">OO, AH! Hey! Oh mio! Tempo perfetto per testare il mio incredibile Transvampcapasitor Voicemodulator. Pronto!?</string>
        <string lang="de">OO, AH! Hallo! Oh mein! Perfekte Zeit, um meinen unglaublichen Transvamp-Kondensator Voicemodulator auszuprobieren. Bereit!?</string>
        <string lang="es">OO, AH! ¡Oye! ¡Oh mi! El momento perfecto para probar mi Increíble Transvampcapasitor Voicemodulator. ¿¡Listo!?</string>
        <string lang="pt">OO, AH! Ei! Oh meu! Perfeito tempo para testar o meu Increíble Transvampcapasitor Voicemodulator. Pronto!?</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_fusion_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">VAH VAH VAHHHH! Vhappy Vhalloween von vhe vount vof vhree! Vhan. Vwo. VHREEEEE!!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">VAH VAH VAHHHH! Joyeux Halloween au compte de trois! Un. Deux. TROIS!!!</string>
        <string lang="it">VAH VAH VAHHHH! Happy Halloween sul conte di tre! Uno. Due. TRE!!!</string>
        <string lang="de">VAH VAH VAHHHH! Happy Halloween in der Zählung von drei! Eins. Zwei. DREI!!!</string>
        <string lang="es">VAH VAH VAHHHH! ¡Feliz Halloween a la cuenta de tres! Uno. Dos. ¡¡¡TRES!!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">VAH VAH VAHHHH! Feliz Halloween na contagem de três! 1. Dois. TRÊS!!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_familiarstable_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">I spent all year on this costume! What do you think???</string>
        <string lang="fr">J'ai passé toute l'année sur ce costume! Qu'est-ce que tu penses???</string>
        <string lang="it">Ho passato tutto l'anno su questo costume! Cosa ne pensi???</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich habe das ganze Jahr mit diesem Kostüm verbracht! Was denken Sie???</string>
        <string lang="es">Pasé todo el año con este disfraz! ¿¿¿Qué piensas???</string>
        <string lang="pt">Passei o ano inteiro nesta fantasia! O que você acha???</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_familiarstable_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ha! IM MESSIN WITH YOU! Take this and GO AWAY.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ha! JE TE TAQUINE! Prenez ceci et partez.</string>
        <string lang="it">Ha! Sto mettendo insieme a te! Prendi questo e andate via.</string>
        <string lang="de">Ha! Ich bin mit dir verheiratet! Nimm das und geh weg.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Decir ah! ¡ESTOY JUGANDO CONTIGO! Toma esto y VAYA LEJOS.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ha! Estou MENSANDO COM VOCÊ! Pegue isso e vá embora.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_rifts_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ugh! Fine. Take this. Leave me alone.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Pouah! Bien. Prends ça. Laisse-moi tranquille.</string>
        <string lang="it">Ugh! Belle. Prendi questo. Lasciami solo.</string>
        <string lang="de">Pfui! Fein. Nimm das. Lass mich allein.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Uf! Multa. Toma esto. Déjame solo.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ugh! Bem. Pegue isso. Me deixe em paz.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_gauntlet_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Yah! It's strwing bwean! YAHHH. Get to da Hallowweennn!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Yah! Son haricot de ficelle! YAH. Arrivez à l'Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="it">Yah! Il suo fagiolo di stringa! YAH. Vieni al Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="de">Yah! Seine Bohne! YAH. Komm zum Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Yah! ¡Su judía de hilo! YAH. ¡Llega al Halloween!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Yah! Seu feijão de cordas! YAH. Chegue ao Halloween!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_fishing_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">'ey! mucker! oi'm so starval! oi 'av naw idea why! lets go ter boozer!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_enchants_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">A bag of candy, sugary treats? I'd rather have spoonful of toad puke and pengey feets!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Un sac de bonbons, des friandises sucrées? Je préfère avoir une cuillerée de vomi de crapaud et des pieds de pengey!</string>
        <string lang="it">Un sacchetto di caramelle, zuccherate? Preferirei cucchiaiate di bricolage e pensieri!</string>
        <string lang="de">Eine Tüte mit Süßigkeiten, süße Leckereien? Ich hätte lieber Löffel Kröte und Füßchen!</string>
        <string lang="es">Una bolsa de dulces, golosinas azucaradas? ¡Prefiero tener una cucharada de mierda de sapo y pendeja!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Um saco de doces e guloseimas açucaradas? Eu preferiria ter uma colher de sapos de vomito e pengey!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_enchants_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">Give me that Fish eye and toad spleen if you please, oh yes did I forget... HAPPY HALLOWEEEEEN.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Donne-moi cet œil de poisson et ce spleen de crapaud si tu veux, oh oui j'ai oublié ... HAPPY HALLOWEEN.</string>
        <string lang="it">Dammi l'occhio di pesce e la milza del rospo se lo desideri, oh sì, ho dimenticato ... HAPPY HALLOWEEN.</string>
        <string lang="de">Gib mir das Fischauge und kröte Milz, wenn du willst, oh ja, habe ich vergessen ... HAPPY HALLOWEEN.</string>
        <string lang="es">Dame ese ojo de pez y bazo de sapo, por favor, oh sí, lo olvidé ... FELIZ HALLOWEEN.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Me dê esse olho de peixe e sapo sapo se você quiser, oh, sim eu esqueci ... HAPPY HALLOWEEN.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_halloween_brawl_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">How do you like my Xaren costume!? Winner of the best costume every year since the Xaren has been Xaren!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Comment aimes-tu mon costume Xaren? Gagnant du meilleur costume chaque année depuis que le Xaren a été Xaren!</string>
        <string lang="it">Come ti piace il mio costume Xaren? Vincitore del miglior costume ogni anno da quando Xaren è stato Xaren!</string>
        <string lang="de">Wie gefällt dir mein Xaren Kostüm? Gewinner des besten Kostüms seit Xaren Xaren!</string>
        <string lang="es">¿Qué te parece mi disfraz de Xaren? ¡Ganador del mejor disfraz todos los años desde que Xaren ha sido Xaren!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Como você gosta do meu traje Xaren? Vencedor da melhor fantasia todos os anos desde que o Xaren foi Xaren!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <!-- Thanksgiving -->
    
    <ref link="dialog_thanksgiving_turkey_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">GOBBLE GOBBLE!!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">GLOUGLOU GLOUGLOU!!!</string>
        <string lang="it">GOBBLE GOBBLE!</string>
        <string lang="de">TRUT TRUT!!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡¡GLUP GLUP!!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">GLUGLU GLUGLU!!!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <!-- Winter -->
    
    <ref link="dialog_winter_quest_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ah, Hero! You look mighty chilly. Have this Coco I made. I used some of Quinn's slop to give it a real kick!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Ah, héros! Vous avez l'air très froid. J'ai ce Coco que j'ai fait. J'ai utilisé une partie du slop de Quinn pour lui donner un vrai coup de pied!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ah, eroe! Sembri possente freddo. Ho fatto questo Coco. Ho usato un po 'di slop di Quinn per dargli un calcio vero!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ah, Held! Du siehst sehr kühl aus. Habe dieses Coco gemacht. Ich habe einige von Quinns Slop benutzt, um ihm einen echten Kick zu geben!</string>
        <string lang="es">Ah, héroe! Te ves muy frío. Tengo este Coco que hice. ¡Usé algo de la basura de Quinn para darle una patada real!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ah, herói! Você parece poderoso. Tenho esse Coco que fiz. Usei um pouco de Quinn para dar-lhe um verdadeiro chute!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    
    <!-- Mount Launch -->
    
    <ref link="dialog_mount_launch_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Hey! Pixelbrain!! I was cookin' some gross !material!29!material! for dinner and I made too much</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hey! Pixel cerveau !! Je cuisinais du !material!29!material! grossier pour le dîner et j'en faisais trop</string>
        <string lang="it">Hey! Cervello Pixel !! Stavo cucinando un po 'di !material!29!material! per cena e ne ho fatti troppo</string>
        <string lang="de">Hallo! Pixel Gehirn !! Ich kochte ein wenig !material!29!material! zum Abendessen und ich habe zu viel gemacht</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Oye! Pixel cerebro !! Estuve cocinando un !material!29!material! asqueroso para la cena e hice demasiado</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ei! Pixel brain !! Eu estava cozinhando um pouco de !material!29!material! para jantar e eu fiz muito</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_mount_launch_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">I have some leftovers, you can have em... if you just stop pestering me all time!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">J'ai quelques restes, tu peux les avoir ... si tu arrêtes juste de me harceler tout le temps !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ho degli avanzi, li puoi avere ... se smetti di tormentarmi tutto il tempo !!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich habe ein paar Überreste, du kannst sie haben ... wenn du einfach aufhörst, mich die ganze Zeit zu belästigen !!</string>
        <string lang="es">Tengo algunas sobras, puedes tenerlas ... ¡si dejas de fastidiarme todo el tiempo!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Tenho algumas sobras, você pode tê-las ... se você simplesmente parar de me incomodar o tempo todo!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    
    <!-- Fishing -->
    <ref link="dialog_fishing_daily_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oi oi!! Gud deh! Awe rite th' coozin' is haur! Prepaur to set sail to mah secrit Fishin' Island!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Hey! Bonne journée. Le bateau est là. Préparez-vous à mettre le cap sur mon île de pêche secrète!</string>
        <string lang="it">Hey! Buona giornata. La barca è qui. Preparati a salpare per la mia isola segreta di pescatori!</string>
        <string lang="de">Hallo! Schönen Tag. Das Boot ist hier. Bereite dich darauf vor, zu meiner geheimen Angelinsel zu segeln!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Oye! Buen día. El bote está aquí. ¡Prepárate para zarpar hacia mi isla de pesca secreta!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Ei! Dia bom. O barco está aqui. Prepare-se para navegar para minha ilha de pesca secreta!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_fishing_daily_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Oh nae, Im not gonnae wi' ye, Ah cannae stain me trouble and strife. Bless 'er sool, she alweys naggin' me! Oi! Tak' thes bait!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Je ne vais pas avec toi, je ne peux pas supporter ma femme. Bénis son âme, elle me harcèle toujours! Oh, prends ça!</string>
        <string lang="it">Non vengo con te, non sopporto mia moglie. Benedici la sua anima, lei mi tormenta sempre! Oh, prendi questo!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich gehe nicht mit dir, ich kann meine Frau nicht ausstehen. Segne ihre Seele, sie nörgelt mich immer! Oh, nimm das!</string>
        <string lang="es">No iré contigo, no puedo soportar a mi esposa. ¡Bendita sea su alma, ella siempre me regaña! Oh, toma esto!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Não vou com você, não posso suportar minha esposa. Abençoe sua alma, ela sempre me irrita! Oh, pegue isso!</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    <ref link="dialog_fishing_shop_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Awrite Brammer! Welcome tae th' Fishing Shop! Hae ye seen mah handsome Ishy. Ah miss heem sae much! He hasn't bin haem in yaers!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Salut! Bienvenue à la boutique de pêche! Avez-vous vu mon Ismaël. Il me manque tellement! Il n'a pas été à la maison depuis des années.</string>
        <string lang="it">Ciao! Benvenuti nel negozio di pesca! Hai visto il mio Ismaele. Lui mi manca così tanto! Non è tornato a casa da anni.</string>
        <string lang="de">Hallo! Willkommen im Angelgeschäft! Hast du meinen Ismael gesehen? Ich vermisse ihn so sehr! Er war seit Jahren nicht mehr zu Hause.</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Hola! Bienvenido a la tienda de pesca! ¿Has visto a mi Ishmael? ¡Yo lo extraño mucho! No ha estado en casa en años.</string>
        <string lang="pt">Olá! Bem-vindo à loja de pesca! Você já viu meu Ismael? Sinto muita falta dele! Ele não esteve em casa há anos.</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_fishing_shop_frame_3_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">If ye see heem teel heem ah miss heem sae much. Ah want tae kiss Ishy's wee cheeks.</string>
        <string lang="fr">Si vous le voyez lui dire qu'il me manque tellement. Je veux embrasser les petites joues d'Ismaël</string>
        <string lang="it">Se lo vedi, digli che mi manca così tanto. Voglio baciare le guance di Ismaele</string>
        <string lang="de">Wenn Sie ihn sehen, sagen Sie ihm, ich vermisse ihn so sehr. Ich möchte Ishmaels kleine Wangen küssen</string>
        <string lang="es">Si lo ves, dile que lo extraño tanto. Quiero besar las pequeñas mejillas de Ishmael</string>
        <string lang="pt">Se você vê-lo, diga a ele que eu sinto tanto falta dele. Eu quero beijar pequenas bochechas de Ishmaels</string>
    </ref>
    
    
    
    
    <!-- NBP -->
    
    <ref link="dialog_nbp_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Psst... hey! Looks like you could use a little help!</string>
        <string lang="fr">Psst... Hé ! On dirait que tu as besoin d'aide !</string>
        <string lang="it">Psst... Ehi! Hai l'aria di aver bisogno di un aiutino!</string>
        <string lang="de">Psst ... hey! Sieht aus, als könntest du etwas Hilfe gebrauchen!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡Chsss... eh! ¡Parece que no te vendría mal un poco de ayuda!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Psiu... ei! Acho que você tá precisando de ajuda!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_nbp_frame_1_content_2_desc">
        <string lang="en">I've got a deal for you!!</string>
        <string lang="fr">J'ai une proposition à te faire !!</string>
        <string lang="it">Ho un affare per te!</string>
        <string lang="de">Ich habe ein Angebot für dich!!</string>
        <string lang="es">¡¡Te propongo un trato!!</string>
        <string lang="pt">Tenho um negócio pra te oferecer!!</string>
    </ref>
    <ref link="dialog_leaderboard_zombie_frame_1_content_1_desc">
        <string lang="en">Ooo gRR GgrrrRR GRRr araaaa uUrrRrR araa RAAAAaA srrr Orr Ooo gRrr ara MrRrrR rAaaaaa grR BBRRAIINNNNNNSS!!</string>
    </ref>
</data>